{
    "questions": [
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Puberun",
                "B. Shakuntala",
                "C. Maniram Devan",
                "D. Ronga Police"
            ],
            "question": "Which one was the first Assamese film to won President's Silver Medal for Best Feature Film?",
            "answer": "D. Ronga Police"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1954",
                "B. 1977",
                "C. 1988",
                "D. 1999"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Assamese film 'Halodhia Choraye Baodhan Khai' wins the Silver and Bronze Leopard Award in Locarno International Film Festival?",
            "answer": "C. 1988"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Firingoti",
                "B. Papori",
                "C. Aparoopa",
                "D. Bonani"
            ],
            "question": "The first film directed by Jahnu Barua was __.",
            "answer": "C. Aparoopa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hiren Gohain",
                "B. Rita Chowdhury",
                "C. Arupa Kalita Patinga",
                "D. Rabindra Sarkar"
            ],
            "question": "The book 'Mariam Astin Athaba Hira Barua' is written by __.",
            "answer": "C. Arupa Kalita Patinga"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Basundhara",
                "B. Othello",
                "C. Bandhon",
                "D. Ajeyo"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese film bagged the National Film Award for 2014?",
            "answer": "D. Ajeyo"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Natraj Theater",
                "B. Hangul Theater",
                "C. Kohinoor Theater",
                "D. Abahan Theater"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first mobile theater of Assam?",
            "answer": "A. Natraj Theater"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Theatre",
                "B. Fine Arts",
                "C. Music",
                "D. Football"
            ],
            "question": "Sobha Brahma was associated with __.",
            "answer": "B. Fine Arts"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 18th September",
                "B. 22nd October",
                "C. 24th November",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Lachit Divas is celebrated on __.",
            "answer": "C. 24th November"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 5th March",
                "B. 12th August",
                "C. 23rd October",
                "D. 2nd December"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Divas is celebrated on __.",
            "answer": "D. 2nd December"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup",
                "B. Goalpara and Kokrajhar",
                "C. Bongaigaon and Kokrajhar",
                "D. Darrang, Barpeta and Nalbari"
            ],
            "question": "Baksa district was created from the parts of which of the following districts?",
            "answer": "A. Barpeta, Nalbari and Kamrup"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chirang",
                "B. South Salmara-Mankachar",
                "C. Kamrup Metro",
                "D. Udalguri"
            ],
            "question": "In terms of area, the smallest district of Assam is __.",
            "answer": "B. South Salmara-Mankachar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Shyam Benegal",
                "B. Amjad Ali",
                "C. Amol Palekar",
                "D. Adoor Gopalakrishnan"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the recipient of Bishwaratna Dr. Bhupen Hazarika International Solidarity Award in 2015?",
            "answer": "D. Adoor Gopalakrishnan"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ram Saraswati",
                "B. Madhab Kandali",
                "C. Ananta kandali",
                "D. Sankardeva"
            ],
            "question": "Who among the following is the first Assamese translator of the Ramayana?",
            "answer": "B. Madhab Kandali"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sudakshina Sarma",
                "B. Anupama Bhattacharya",
                "C. Pratima Pandey Barua",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first Assamese woman to be awarded by the 'Sangeet Natak Akademi'?",
            "answer": "C. Pratima Pandey Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nirmal Bhakat",
                "B. Miri Jiyori",
                "C. Manomoti",
                "D. Donduadrah"
            ],
            "question": "The first novel by Rajanikanta Bordoloi was __.",
            "answer": "B. Miri Jiyori"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chakradhwaj Singha",
                "B. Udayaditya Singha",
                "C. Pratap Singha",
                "D. Jayadhwaj Singha"
            ],
            "question": "During which Ahom King reign, the Saraighat battle was ended with decisive win over Mughal?",
            "answer": "B. Udayaditya Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chakradhwaj Singha",
                "B. Udayaditya Singha",
                "C. Pratap Singha",
                "D. Jayadhwaj Singha"
            ],
            "question": "During which Ahom King reign, the Saraighat battle was ended with decisive win over Mughal?",
            "answer": "B. Udayaditya Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pratap Singha",
                "B. Dihingia Raja",
                "C. Rajeswar Singha",
                "D. Lakshmi Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king created the 'Borbarua' and 'Borphukan' post?",
            "answer": "A. Pratap Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sankardev",
                "B. Madhava Kandali",
                "C. Madhavdev",
                "D. Hema Saraswati"
            ],
            "question": "Who wrote the book 'Bhakti Ratnavali?",
            "answer": "C. Madhavdev"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. January 2001",
                "B. April 2006",
                "C. March 2008",
                "D. January 2010"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam Gas Cracker project was approved in __.",
            "answer": "B. April 2006"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 2nd September",
                "B. 30th October",
                "C. 14th November",
                "D. 10th December"
            ],
            "question": "Swahid Divas is celebrated on __.",
            "answer": "D. 10th December"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Golaghat",
                "B. Goalpara",
                "C. Dhuburi",
                "D. Dibrugarh"
            ],
            "question": "In which district, Sainik School is located?",
            "answer": "B. Goalpara"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Chandradhar Barua",
                "B. Tarun Ram Phukan",
                "C. Gopinath Bordoloi",
                "D. Krishna Nath Sarmah"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the only Assamese who represented India in the First Round Table Conference held at London in 1930?",
            "answer": "A. Chandradhar Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Silchar",
                "B. Jorhat",
                "C. Nagaon",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "The first women's university in Assam \"Assam Women's University\" is located in __.",
            "answer": "B. Jorhat"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Morigaon",
                "B. Raha",
                "C. Nagaon",
                "D. Jorhat"
            ],
            "question": "Assam's only fishery college \"College of Fisheries Science\" is located in __.",
            "answer": "B. Raha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Brahmaputra",
                "B. Lohit",
                "C. Dibang",
                "D. Siang"
            ],
            "question": "The Dhola-Sadiya bridge is built on the _____ river.",
            "answer": "B. Lohit"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jyoti Prasad Agarwala",
                "B. Achyut Lahkar",
                "C. Ratan Lahkar",
                "D. Bishnu Prasad Rab"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as the father of the Bhryamyman or Mobile Theater of Assam?",
            "answer": "B. Achyut Lahkar"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhupen Hazarika",
                "B. Khagen Mahanta",
                "C. Zubeen Garg",
                "D. Jayanta Hazarika"
            ],
            "question": "Which singer is also popularly known as the \"King of Bihu\"?",
            "answer": "B. Khagen Mahanta"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jyotimoti",
                "B. Siraj",
                "C. Indramalati",
                "D. Pioli Phukan"
            ],
            "question": "Which one is the first film where Bhupen Hazarika sings as playback singer?",
            "answer": "C. Indramalati"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bhupen Hazarika",
                "B. Mamoni Raisom Goswami",
                "C. Jitendra Nath Goswami",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first recipient of 'Asom Ratna award'?",
            "answer": "A. Bhupen Hazarika"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dimbeswar Neog",
                "B. Amulya Barua",
                "C. Nabakanta Barua",
                "D. Hiren Bhattacharyya"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese poet is also known as 'Prem aru Rodalir Kobi'?",
            "answer": "D. Hiren Bhattacharyya"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 2001",
                "B. 2000",
                "C. 2004",
                "D. 2008"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Mamoni Raisom Goswami win the 'Jnanpith Award'?",
            "answer": "B. 2000"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Nalini Bala Devi",
                "B. Raghunath Choudhary",
                "C. Nilamani Phookan",
                "D. Hem Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Who had written the poetry anthology 'Alakananda'?",
            "answer": "A. Nalini Bala Devi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Lakshminath Bezbaroa",
                "B. Chandra Kumar Agarwala",
                "C. Satyanath Bora",
                "D. Ananda Chandra Agarwala"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first editor of the Assamese magazine 'Jonaki'?",
            "answer": "B. Chandra Kumar Agarwala"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1856",
                "B. 1889",
                "C. 1880",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "In which year Assamese magazine 'Jonaki' was first published?",
            "answer": "B. 1889"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dimbeswar Neog",
                "B. Nalinidhar Bhattacharya",
                "C. Raghunath Choudhary",
                "D. Nilmoni Phukan"
            ],
            "question": "Who is also known as 'bihogi kobi'?",
            "answer": "C. Raghunath Choudhary"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Dimbeswar Neog",
                "B. Chandra Kumar Agarwala",
                "C. Mahendranath Dekaphukan",
                "D. Benudhar Rajkhowa"
            ],
            "question": "The first Assamese romantic poem 'Bon Kunwori' was written by __.",
            "answer": "B. Chandra Kumar Agarwala"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Benudhar Rajkhowa",
                "B. Shivaram Sarma Bordoloi",
                "C. Lakshiprasad Chaliha",
                "D. Lakhyeswar Sarma"
            ],
            "question": "Who was the first secretary of the 'Oxomiya Bhaxa Unnati Xadhini Xobha'?",
            "answer": "B. Shivaram Sarma Bordoloi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. 1902",
                "B. 1904",
                "C. 1905",
                "D. 1906"
            ],
            "question": "The first modern Assamese theatre hall 'Baan theatre' established at Tezpur in the year ___.",
            "answer": "D. 1906"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Bishnuram Medhi",
                "B. Binanda Chandra Barua",
                "C. Anandaram Dhekial Phukan",
                "D. Ananda Chandra Barua"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese writer is also known as 'Bakulbonor Kavi'?",
            "answer": "D. Ananda Chandra Barua"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hema Saraswati",
                "B. Harivara Vipra",
                "C. Madhava Kandali",
                "D. Kaviratna Saravati"
            ],
            "question": "Who had written the book named 'Prahlada charitra'?",
            "answer": "A. Hema Saraswati"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Ananta Kandali",
                "B. Madhava Kandali",
                "C. Sankardeva",
                "D. Kaviratna Saravati"
            ],
            "question": "Which Assamese poet had translated Valmiki Ramayana into Assamese verse 'Saptakanda Ramayana'?",
            "answer": "B. Madhava Kandali"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Hajo",
                "B. Rangia",
                "C. Batadrava",
                "D. Sualkuchi"
            ],
            "question": "The Assam silk industry is mainly centered in __.",
            "answer": "D. Sualkuchi"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Narayanpur",
                "B. Patbaushi",
                "C. Bordowa",
                "D. Majuli"
            ],
            "question": "Sankaradeva had established the first Naamghar at __.",
            "answer": "C. Bordowa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sankardev",
                "B. Madhabdev",
                "C. Damodardev",
                "D. None of these"
            ],
            "question": "Who had established the 'Barpeta Satra' in Barpeta?",
            "answer": "B. Madhabdev"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Pushya Varman",
                "B. Samudra Varman",
                "C. Mahendra Varman",
                "D. Bhuti Varman"
            ],
            "question": "Who had established the Varman dynasty in Assam?",
            "answer": "A. Pushya Varman"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Gadadhar Singha",
                "B. Sukhrangpha",
                "C. Siva Singha",
                "D. Rudra Singha"
            ],
            "question": "Which Swargadeo shifted the capital of the Ahom Kingdom from Garhgaon to Rangpur?",
            "answer": "D. Rudra Singha"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Sutuphaa",
                "B. Sudangphaa",
                "C. Susenphaa",
                "D. Suphakphaa"
            ],
            "question": "Which Ahom king is also known as 'Bamuni Konwar'?",
            "answer": "B. Sudangphaa"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Raymond W. Beave",
                "B. Nathan Brown",
                "C. Oliver Thomas Cutter",
                "D. Robert Bruce"
            ],
            "question": "Who had discovered Tea plants in Assam in the year 1823?",
            "answer": "D. Robert Bruce"
        },
        {
            "options": [
                "A. Jairam Das Daulatram",
                "B. Saiyid Fazal Ali",
                "C. Vishnu Sahay",
                "D. Braj Kumar Nehru"
            ],
            "question": "Who had conferred Gopinath Bordoloi with the title \"Lokapriya\"?",
            "answer": "A. Jairam Das Daulatram"
        }
    ]
}